What preceded:
Why all the trouble with Partridge
and Gordon if I'm not free?
Just tell me what to do.
-Isn't that clear?
We are only safe
if it has been removed.
You look like a corpse. You were already dead
if I hadn't helped you.
I don't listen to you.
-Listen to yourself.
You were already dead
if I hadn't helped you.
Help us if this works
to the Russian embassy.
We lure Volk to a safe place ...
we kidnap him and force him
to reveal the mole's identity.
Turner blackmails me.
He wants me to trap you.
Drop your charges.
-Not now, Mae.
You had him picked up
because I spoke to Thrush.
I am really sorry.
Sorry to hear that.
-So what they say about you Is true?
Mr. Abbott's not here, Mrs. Larkin.
-He leaked that Piper story.
Why would he make us a bad name
for your benefit?
I find that scary.
Gordon, come on. To breathe.
You trust them
betray her own people?
I have no choice.
But that also applies to her.
I do what you asked.
-Make sure you are available.
Where were you? I'm screwed.
-By who?
Reuel, and the Russians.
Phoenix is ​​gone. Dead, I guess.
Give her time. She'll take it
get in touch as soon as she can.
I said "she," didn't I?
I have a place. Not a real safe house,
but good enough.
Okay, come on.
You're a good friend, Trace.
attract People to Eagle Lane 31
and then?
-there He Is met
stupid plan
I'm here. They are not there yet.
I pretend to be at home.
What did he say?
I did not know
that we played hide and seek.
He gave me an address.
-And?
That's all.
-He'll get you to a metal concert ...
to give you an address?
It was more punk.
-But why?
Maybe he was scared of being on a lake
public place to fall into the trap.
Or he didn't want me to hear
what he said to you.
Or he doesn't want you to trust me.
If you can't understand us, you would
may think we are up to something.
Then that man is a genius.
After you.
How's the patient?
He has to rest that leg for a week.
- Maybe another week.
Wouldn't you stop?
Then you live longer.
And all those stumpers that stop
and then die young?
Are you afraid of that?
That you die young?
My father also died young.
-It was with the CIA.
I think I get it
how it went with Sam.
You can become so straightforward ...
in defending your principles ...
that you forget to follow them.
I think Sam lost out on that.
And you?
Have you lost yourself?
-Not yet, I think.
I don't know what you and Trace are doing,
but please be careful.
Here.
Don't tell anyone.
-I can keep secrets well.
Change does not mean
lose your identity.
Sometimes it means right
find your identity.
Shall we?
How do you feel?
-Like the cheese in a mousetrap.
You're not the only one.
Hi, Paula.
No, why?
Eva?
I am so sorry.
What should I do?
-Come on.
So this is a CIA safe house.
No. We don't yet know who the mole is,
so we can't trust them.
Who lives here then?
Nobody. The owner died
last week. No family.
Wait.
I've been watching the house.
They're in. Only.
Who was that?
Someone I asked to come earlier,
for the sake of my safety.
You mean our safety.
Yes, that's what I meant.
He said they're in there alone.
What are we waiting for?
You thought I did this
would do only with you?
The coast is clear.
The house is empty.
There is nobody.
You are a very good liar.
If you have been betrayed,
it wasn't me.
It is especially clever how you take care of it
that I believe you.
We have to hurry.
So those bad things I do online
read about you, are all correct?
Joe, he's coming to.
I remember you.
Clearly you remember me.
Or you think you know me.
I also knew myself.
What I was and was not capable of.
Torturing someone,
for any reason...
was always something that I consider myself
deemed unable.
Or could be part of it.
The trick is to take it one step at a time
to do.
Ask yourself: Where is the limit
what I don't want to get over
And then you move it.
A little piece.
And then you move it a little further.
And another piece.
Continuously.
Until you are the person you were
barely recognized.
So. Who is your mole?
So she chose you?
Dirty whore.
I think he is jealous.
Maybe he saw
how you took my cock in your mouth.
You have to take care in this business
that you keep your distance.
Then you are better prepared
on the possibility of treason.
I liked her, but she's still a whore.
It is pure business.
It can never be more with a whore.
Maybe we are all whores.
It is rare as someone
retains its honor in this business.
What kind of circus is this?
-Give me a minute. Two minutes.
Your uncle, for example.
He was given a choice that evening.
Not by me, of course, but by
the man you are looking for.
Bob could choose: Must look it
as a suicide or as a raid?
But of course there was also an incursion
his wife be killed.
Your uncle went for the honorable choice.
Joe, that's enough.
-Let me go.
Do not touch me.
-Come to yourself.
Is everything alright?
-I thought I could count on you.
Then you can too.
It just has to look good.
This was not our plan.
This is a new plan,
where we both get what we want.
This is going to be messy. We have to cut down,
he never lets go.
Not this way. He is trained
to endure a lot more.
What do you suggest?
-Chop off his fingers.
When there are no more fingers,
make up something else.
What are you talking about?
Where are you going?
Give him some water.
We are torturing him.
-I know how It works.
Brute force is not enough.
I want to try something different.
-Leave her.
Water?
-No.
I was already scared
that you would frame me.
I prepared for it,
and yet you did it.
Tell me.
How did you do it?
By not knowing what I was going to do
until the moment was there.
By just being true to myself.
You could do that too.
Adapt to the circumstances
and make sure you survive.
They'll make a deal with you.
Cigarette?
-Go ahead.
I will not bite you.
First I am betrayed
by my best friend.
Then by a woman
for whom I got feelings.
I fell for it again.
I haven't played a game with you.
My feelings for you are real.
But I think it's too late for that now.
My grandfather was in Germany
during the occupation ...
after the Great Patriotic War.
He fell for a German beauty.
They had a child
and she also fell for him.
In that order.
Early in their relationship
love came from one side.
But pure love
defies logic ...
and all circumstances.
If I saw a future for us
I would tell them everything.
I'm tired of it, Katya.
Dear...
Who is it? Say it.
Tell me who it is. Who is it?
He is dead.
Piece of shit.
Sorry. I had rang the doorbell.
-Carla.
I was with the director. Nobody above
GS-15 was at the CIMC office.
You're the only one on the seventh floor
who knows the details of the Piper case.
Now that he's dead ...
He committed suicide in his cell.
Now everyone wants information.
Why?
-If a CIA agent dies ...
Why did he commit suicide?
-As double spy unmasked ...
But he was innocent.
He was not the mole.
How do you know that?
-I was in Bob's office that fateful night.
There was nothing to be found in his files. So
Gordon's file was put there later.
Why didn't you say anything?
-I wanted to sabotage Robin Larkin.
So you knew there was another mole
walked around ...
that was a danger to our people,
and you said nothing because of a feud?
I suffered a long time
taken a wrong turn ...
and continued with that.
I'm afraid
that I have lost my way terribly.
I see your wound is already healing
comrade.
I have some questions for you
about that day.
How did you end up at that lake?
People traced Sirin
to a secluded house.
We lured Volk to the house
to separate him from his team.
You wanted it one on one?
-He was with a woman.
We kidnapped them.
It was a trap.
They were waiting for us.
The woman escaped.
I escaped.
-How?
They were torturing People.
We don't torture people.
Does he have the informant's name
given?
No.
- Would He Give in under pressure?
No, I do not think so.
Where was Robin Larkin in this story?
I have her before Gordon's arrest
last seen.
How does her disappearance fit
altogether?
I think she was killed
to protect the mole.
But she disappeared
after Piper was arrested.
Unless you have reasons to suspect
that Piper was not the mole.
I think he was framed.
I don't know who the mole is.
I'm glad you're okay.
-Is everything alright? You weren't in the hospital.
I can not do it.
Not after Gordon.
I explained that.
-you said everything Would be fine.
And I trusted you.
We were at their home
when you did that to him.
He was our friend.
-I know.
But you don't have all the facts.
-That's right.
And you can't give me that either,
or?
That's why I was already cautious
towards you.
I've made that mistake before.
I would
that you had an idea ...
of the shit I had to do
to make it work between us.
Really, I wish you knew that.
Even more confidential bullshit.
-That's my job.
That is precisely the problem.
Had that figured out
before you misled me.
I think you did that yourself.
- Get It on.
Out of my house.
Are you deaf?
-everything fine?
Tracy just left.
Goodbye, Mr. Crane.
Is everything alright?
Sorry.
Surprisingly, the Deputy Director of
the CIA at a traitor's funeral.
We both know that Gordon doesn't
was a traitor. The CIA also knows ...
but they never admit that.
I've been to funerals before ...
of people before whose death
I felt responsible.
But I am determined
make sure this is the last one.
And if I'm committed to you
to kill? To be sure?
You get a taste for it, Joe.
Watch out.
But I'm going to retire and plan to
make a full confession.
We cannot do anything
with what is between you and your god.
That's why I intend to use it
to make a more public forum.
Take care of yourself, Joe.
Capitol Hill is getting ready ...
for the testimony
from CIA CEO Reuel Abbott.
Is everything alright?
The focus will be on the allegations
from former CIA agent Marty Frost.
Even if Abbott only a part
of the Frost file confirms ...
that could have major implications for
the US intelligence services.
For more on Abbott's testimony
we go to the Capitol.
I will not scream.
I know.
Hey everything okay?
-Reuel Abbott Is dead.
Turn on the TV.
Wait a second.
It has just been confirmed that CIA CEO
Reuel Abbott has been found dead ...
in his pool.
The police investigation is still ongoing.
I will call you back.
All kinds of theories are circulating
about the suspicious timing ...
just before Abbott's testimony
for Congress.
Say goodbye, Mr. Crane.
Bastards.
-Congratulations.
Well deserved.
-We're going to miss you.
Hey, I think I got a bite.
To catch up.
A big.
-We can eat that.
We keep it.
-Kiss.
Gatver, Dad.
-Look.
Super. I am a real fisherman.
-Well done.
I am not armed.
-You can't be too careful.
Can I sit with you?
Surprised to see me?
No. After what we've been through ...
we are both an interesting recruit
for the other.
If you hadn't approached me,
I had approached you.
I don't have to recruit you, Potoo.
-Do I have to understand what that means?
I recognized your voice by the lake.
I just couldn't remember what.
Suddenly I knew. I was in the car
that night when you called Volk ...
to say Joe
was on the way to Vasili.
You are just like me.
You play for both teams.
You were a Folk man in the safe house, huh?
The one he just counted on.
You untied it.
And you shot, so you were the hero.
How far-fetched.
It seems like the spy novel.
Played very cleverly.
I would have done the same.
If what you say is true ...
we both have something where we
to pick up the other.
Then we are still ...
-Even? Exactly what I thought myself.
What are you doing here?
I am back with the SVR.
I want to know if my secret is safe.
Well?
-I have stopped.
At the CIA.
-No, with everything.
So you will no longer report
to Moscow?
Beautiful.
Have a nice life.
What are you doing here?
I have thought a lot about this house.
-Yes? how so?
How long you have it
and how much it must have cost you.
How long have you been doing this?
-what are you talking about?
I have stopped.
- At the CIA.
No, with everything.
So you will no longer report
to Moscow?
That was a game.
I wanted to recruit her as an informant.
You were only late.
She is now my informant.
She is a Russian spy. Do you believe...
-She's very convincing.
This is what they do. They are good at it.
They did it with Gordon, and now ...
It's what you do.
So you have already decided.
You always talk, don't you?
People are often outside the city
good of confidence.
They don't lock their door
and have no alarm.
You just wanted to shoot me?
-Isn't that what you did to Bob?
I made up my mind to tell you quietly
what I was going to do to you.
Give you the chance to have your say.
I wanted you to know
that this was not revenge ...
but justice.
But you know, I lied to myself.
Because what I really want,
is seeing that look in your eyes ...
when you realize it's over.
I've heard stories about what's going on
happened at the lake. Is it true?
Depends what you heard.
I was friends with Tracy Crane.
He was one of the good guys.
Unbelievable that he is no longer there.
Do you want to know what I heard?
-what have you heard?
It was revenge from the Russians
for Gordon Piper.
For revealing their mole.
After you.
CIA headquarters, Virginia
Last year we focused all our attention
on Boko Haram and IS in West Africa.
We have shifted our focus
to a new game.
We now play chess with the Chinese
and Africa is the sign.
Half of this room is busy ours
to strengthen its military position there.
The other half tries to prevent
that the Chinese do the same.
A dirty game,
but it's us or them, right?
I sit there. Just scream
if you want to smoke.