Previously on "Condor"...
Joe, I need you to listen
to me very carefully.
You're not going to take me to Vasili?
I'm taking you to the end of track 11.
You can take yourself.
80 Bowery Street, Chevy Chase, Maryland.
Thank you for seeing me, Senator Thrush.
I saw it. My husband
who I thought I knew
ordering the death
of one of our friends.
Reuel has been operating out
of bounds for far too long.
I don't want to pressure you
into saying something
you're not ready to say.
I'm ready.
- You were swatted.
- Like a fly?
- This feels personal.
- You would even say childish.
Get in.
I think Joe Turner's on
his way to meet Vasili Sirin.
I'm already on him.
Did you follow him?
Where has he been?
He had a meeting at Union Station.
Who with?
I couldn't see.
I can't do this anymore.
I feel like they know.
You are safe. Not even my
own people know who you are.
It's not your people
that I'm worried about.
He's stopped.
Make a sound and I'll slit your throat.
(GUN COCKING)
Hey, man.
She found you.
(GUNSHOTS)
I need you to tell me who the mole is.
I think an innocent man is
going to take the fall for him.
If you tell me who it is,
then I can clear his name.
I would like to tell you,
but I don't know.
Volk is hunting you, because he
told you the name of his asset.
No, he knows he said too much
but he was so drunk he doesn't remember
exactly what it is he said to me.
I am only fucking here
because you used me.
I'm sorry, Joe.
We should go. The
hunters will be here soon.
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
- Synced and corrected by Firefly -
- www.addic7ed.com -
(PANTING)
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- (BIRD CHIRPING)
- (MUSIC CONTINUES)
- (LEAVES RUSTLING)
Come on.
Teams of two, 50 meters apart.
- (CHAINS RATTLING)
- (DOGS BARKING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(RATTLING, BARKING CONTINUES)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(DRONE WHIRRING)
(WHIRRING CONTINUES)
- Come with me.
- Where to?
We'll leave the hunt to the hunters.
(BARKING CONTINUES)
(MUFFLED PANTING)
(PANTING CONTINUES)
Spread out!
- (RUSTLING)
- (GRUNTING)
(RUSTLING CONTINUES)
(BARKING IN DISTANCE)
Shit.
(GRUNTING)
(BARKING CONTINUES)
(RUSTLING)
(BARKING INTENSIFIES)
(GUNSHOTS)
(BARKING STOPS)
(PANTING)
Jesus Christ. You used me as bait?
- Not as bait, as a lure.
- (GUN COCKING)
There's really a difference?
A lure, you hope to get back.
How many people have to
die so that you can live?
Do you want to surrender?
(GRUNTS) They'll be here any minute.
We'll go to the water.
(BARKING IN DISTANCE)
(CROWS CAWING)
How many people died in Iraq
the first two times around?
Can anybody explain to
me what they died for?
And you really want to go back?
Look, (STAMMERS) I get it.
It's a fraught subject for you.
You saw a lot of friends die over there
and you want to believe that
their sacrifice was meaningful.
But knowing what you know now,
would you really send
them all over again?
(SCOFFS, CHUCKLES)
What, it's funny? (STAMMERS)
Am I funny to you?
Why can't we just talk
about music or something?
I mean, do you ever just go to movies?
Try turning this thing off?
Joe, I feel bad for the hamster.
No, man, I am serious.
It's not long before Sammy is
old enough to go up there himself.
Would you let him go?
Yeah, I would. Yeah, I would.
Mae, she wouldn't allow it.
But, yeah, if it were
up to me, absolutely.
Ah! How can you possibly say that?
(WATER RUNNING)
All right, Joe. Imagine that there
is a man drowning in this river.
All right? You don't know
the guy. He's nobody to you.
For all you know he might
beat his wife and his kids,
and maybe the world's a
better-off place without him.
But all you know is that
there is a human being,
screaming over there and you hear him.
So what do you do? Do you just
stand here and watch him die?
Or do you jump in and
try to save his life?
All right, uh...
The current is too fast.
So, if I jumped in there's a good
chance that we both drown.
So, I would, er...
find a long branch and
used it to pull him out.
(LAUGHS)
And there's the difference
between you and me, Joe.
Okay, so you find a branch,
or maybe you don't.
Maybe you pull him out.
Maybe the branch snaps.
Maybe he drowns before
he can grab ahold of it.
But whatever happens you tell yourself
that you did everything that you could.
But that's a lie because
you didn't risk anything.
So, you would just jump in?
- Without a second thought.
- It's reckless.
- Life is not always safe.
- You would probably die.
- For sure.
- Maybe.
You know what? If I lived though,
I wouldn't have any regrets.
(STAMMERS) That's what
I want for my sons.
That's what I want for my friends.
Do you know what your problem is?
You overthink everything.
You don't commit.
Well, indecision just leads
to somebody else's
decisions being made for you.
Sometimes you gotta
fucking jump in the river.
(WATER RUNNING INTENSIFIES)
It's moving too fast.
We can ride the current downstream.
We've no idea what's downstream.
It'll confuse the dogs.
We'll freeze to death!
Only if we don't drown in the rapids.
- (DOGS BARKING)
- (SIGHS)
Or we can just stand
here and wait to get shot.
What do you want to do?
(DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING)
_
(GASPING, PANTING)
What is it? Hey. Hey.
Are you okay? Hey. Hey...
Hey. Look at me. You're okay.
You're okay. You're okay.
You're okay. Hey.
I've got you. I've got you. You're okay.
Say it, say that you're okay.
- (REPEATS) I'm okay.
- You're okay.
Hey.
Bad dream?
Hey, it's okay.
- (PANTING)
- It's okay.
Hey. Look at me.
Hey. You're back in real life, okay?
We're at your lake house.
We are together,
everything is good, okay?
- Yeah.
- Come here. It's okay.
It was just a dream.
- Sorry.
- No, it's okay.
- I got you.
- (SIGHS)
It's okay.
- What are you thinking about?
- The day we met.
(CHUCKLING)
You looked so lost the first
time I saw you, so innocent.
I liked you right away.
I just had a panic attack.
I had to leave the church
before the service was over.
Is that something that
happens to you often?
No, it never happened to me before.
Hmm.
What do you think caused it?
I don't know. Maybe God was
sending me out to meet you.
(CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING) Why would God care?
Oh, I don't know. Maybe he wanted
me to re-examine my life
- or become a better person.
- Hmm.
But why would the
all-powerful God you pray to
care at all?
Maybe for the same reason that
we care about our children.
Well, I think...
I think you are already a good person.
Why?
Because I wouldn't
be with you otherwise.
You dedicate your life to helping
people, to making them safer.
Well, if that's why you like me,
I'd better go to work today.
- (GASPS)
- (SCOFFS)
(GRUNTS)
(MOANING)
(SIGHS)
(BIRD CHIRPING)
(SIGHS HAPPILY)
Reuel?
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
- (WIND BLOWING)
- Who would do such an awful thing?
- (LEAVES RUSTLING)
- _
- (CROWS CAWING)
I guess that would be weird, right?
You and I would be stepbrothers.
My mom always wanted to have more kids.
She had a miscarriage
when I was in third grade.
Uh, she and my dad wanted
to have a big family,
but, you know after she lost...
(PHONE RINGING)
Speak of the devil... Hang on, dude.
- Hey, Mom.
- Hey, how are you?
I was just talking to Anders
- about you and Mr. Crane having a baby.
- (CHUCKLING)
Okay, calm down. We're
just away for the weekend.
- Are you having fun?
- I am.
- Mr. Crane's a nice guy.
- Yeah, I think so too.
I wanted to remind you
that you have that AP
English prep class tonight.
- Yeah, I know, I know.
- Okay, good.
I miss you guys.
- Okay, I'll call you later.
- Bye... bye, bye.
Bye.
Turner and Sirin are together.
I could already be blown.
They're trapped in the woods.
We're jamming all the cell signals.
It's only a matter of
time before we get them.
- Fuck!
- Calm down.
- Don't tell me to calm down.
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
Sirin shouldn't know my name
and shouldn't even know I exist.
Where are you?
Don't worry about me, I'm safe.
You could be in Moscow by morning.
That's not an option. Moscow
isn't part of my plans.
- I gotta go.
- I'll call you when I know more.
Okay kiddo, have fun on your
camping trip. I love you.
- Was that Anders?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh my God, did he tell you what he
and Sammy were just talking about?
No, what were they talking about?
I'm not even gonna go there.
- Okay.
- (BOTH CHUCKLING)
- So beautiful.
- Yeah, it is, isn't it?
You know, I found this
place completely by accident.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
I was going to meet this guy
and he gave me the wrong address. So...
I ended up here, instead of
where we were supposed to meet.
Life just seemed so simple.
I wanted a piece of
that simplicity for myself.
I can see why.
Are you hungry, do you want breakfast?
Yes! What are you making?
(CHUCKLING)
(INDISTINCT NOISE IN DISTANCE)
(GASPS)
(REFRIGERATOR DOOR CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(KEYS CLACKING)
_
(LAPTOP LID CLOSES)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(VEHICLES PASSING BY)
(SIREN BLARING)
(HONKING)
(CLATTERING IN BIN)
There, you can bring it to him now.
You're the boss, but do
you think it's a good idea
to torment him like this?
(CLICKS TONGUE) You're right.
About you being the boss?
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(BEEPS, DOOR OPENS)
(CREAKING, DOOR CLOSES)
(SIGHS)
(BEEPS, DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
Is this your handiwork, Robin?
Why are you making this so personal?
Is it because your husband
left you for another man?
Not that that part matters,
but, is that what this is about? Huh?
You see me with my happy family...
and you want to drag us
down with you. Is that it?
Well, you won't succeed.
I didn't do what you say I did
and you're not going to break me.
Do you hear me, Robin?
You're not going to break me.
- Challenge accepted.
- (DOOR OPENS)
- Ma'am, it's about CHS Phoenix.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
What about it?
In the draft box of the
Gmail account you use,
he sent up an SOS.
(OBJECT CLATTERING)
What does the message say?
"My people are on to
me. I'm being watched.
I haven't much time. Requesting asylum".
- How shall I handle it?
- (SIGHS) Um...
Phoenix has earned his retirement.
Initiate protocols.
I'll meet him tonight.
- And get me an overwatch for 20:00 hours.
- Yes, ma'am.
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(KEYS CLACKING)
- Boo.
- (GASPS)
- You had me there.
- You were lost in thought.
I was on autopilot.
I heard about a man in Norway.
He had his GPS set
for the Arctic tundra.
Hmm.
These days people do what
their gadgets tell them to do.
I miss the simplicity of floor plans.
I have never been able to read maps.
(BOTH CHUCKLING)
- Do you want to have lunch today?
- Fine.
Cool.
(KEYS CLACKING)
(PHONE RINGING)
Have you found them?
(PHONE CLATTERS ON TABLE)
(RUSTLING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWS CAWING)
(DOOR OPENS, CREAKS)
- Hey.
- (DOOR CLOSES)
- Got a room?
- What happened to you?
- Oh, I took a swim in the river.
- With your clothes on?
Yeah, I didn't want them to get stolen.
(CLICKS TONGUE) Great.
So, how about that room?
- That'll be 60.
- All right.
All right. Thank you.
(DOOR OPENS, CREAKS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
Do you want to tell me about your dream?
What dream?
It wasn't that bad, really.
It was bad enough to make you
jump out of bed this morning.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
It was just about someone from my past.
I'm sorry if I scared you.
That old cliché about the
spy's past catching up with him.
Yeah.
Guess my dreams aren't
very original, are they?
Well then, it's a good thing
that your dreams
aren't what interest me about you.
Oh, yeah? What does
interest you about me?
(KISSING)
- I have an idea.
- Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
I think...
- I know what your idea is.
- Hmm.
Let's go fishing.
That is exactly what I thought
you were going to say.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(PHONE VIBRATING)
Uh...
Sorry, I gotta take
this. I'll be right back.
Hey!
So, I heard a rumor that
you went away on vacation
and I knew that had to be bullshit
so I'm calling to find out what time
you're coming into the office today.
This is all just getting
to me, you know?
Oh, you can't run away
from your problems.
Aren't you the one who
told me to recuse myself?
That doesn't sound familiar.
So, how much time do you feel you need
before you can bring
them back to the office?
I'm feeling phantom pain
from losing my right arm.
Aw, aren't you sweet?
I'll see you Monday.
(PHONE CLATTERS)
(SIGHS)
(VEHICLES PASSING BY)
(BIRDS CAWING)
(LIGHTER CLICKING)
Hey, bud. Bum a smoke?
Yeah. Sure, yeah.
- You're Jefferson, right?
- Huh?
(LIGHTER CLICKING)
Jefferson High.
- Oh. No, no, no, I'm just passing through.
- Really?
I was sure you look familiar.
- Oh, yeah?
- Hmm.
No, no, no, I get that a lot, though.
Yeah, I'm getting out of here myself.
Oh, yeah? Where you going?
I'm not sure yet.
I had a job lined up out
in California for a minute,
but it didn't work out.
Right.
You know, across the river in D.C.
people no better than you and me
are making history as we speak.
But this place might as
well be a million miles away.
Yeah?
Hey, mind if I bum one for the road?
Sure, buddy.
- You know what? Take two.
- Thanks.
- Take it easy.
- Mm-hmm.
(BIRDS CAWING)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(CIGARETTE SIZZLING)
(BULLETS CLICKING)
- (KNOCK AT DOOR)
- (GASPS)
(GUN COCKING)
(LOCK CLICKING, DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES, LOCK CLICKS)
I need to make a phone call.
There is someone I trust.
I don't trust anybody but you.
Yeah, well, we're stuck
in a motel room...
when just over there across the river
there is an entire counter
intelligence case open
and being worked by the professionals.
I can at least tell them what we know,
and find out what they know.
(SIGHS)
Okay.
(PAPER BAG RUSTLING)
I didn't start this war.
It was declared on me.
But I sure as hell
don't want to lose it.
Reuel...
- We have the 911 call, right?
- Yes, but...
And voice synthesis confirms, it's him.
Yes, but he's a 17-year-old.
He sent a SWAT team to my home...
... destroyed my lawn. His
age is hardly relevant.
The courts are taking
swatting very seriously.
They're prosecuting cases
with deterrence in mind.
That's good. Maybe our
little friend will be deterred
from future acts of
aggression on his elders.
I'm saying he could go
to jail... for a long time.
Maybe you should turn the other cheek.
The only justice is God's justice.
Fine, hold off, for now.
Okay, boss.
(DOOR CLOSES)
(PAPER RUSTLING)
- (KNOCK AT DOOR)
- (GASPS)
(DOOR SLIDES OPEN)
- I've arranged lunch.
- I've got an appointment with Polina.
It is already waiting for us.
Come on, I insist.
The day a fish is caught
is the worst day of its life.
- Do you know why?
- Because it dies and gets eaten.
Yeah, obviously. (CHUCKLING)
But the other really shitty
reason beyond that is...
Here's a fish...
- (WHIRRING)
- And...
... it's chasing its prey.
Thinking it's about to eat.
Now, imagine you
ordered a cheeseburger...
and you're salivating. You're
about to take that first bite...
and all of a sudden, (GROWLS)
the cheeseburger eats you.
That's what it feels like to be a fish.
- That really fucked up.
- Right?
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(PHONE RINGING)
(DOOR SLIDES, CLOSES)
Fresh from the oven.
(DRINK POURING)
(SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
(BOTTLE CLATTERS ON TABLE)
To our good health.
(GLASSES CLINKING)
(GLASSES CLATTER ON TABLE)
(SIGHS)
Come on, eat up. It's sturgeon.
(SPOONS CLINKING)
(DRINK POURING)
I read about a man
who followed his GPS...
- and ended up on the Arctic tundra.
- (ALL CHUCKLE)
(CLEARS THROAT)
I'm sorry, I'm a little tired.
I didn't sleep very well.
I have a leak at home. Drip,
drip, drip. The whole night.
Sorry. What did you say again?
Nothing.
- (WATER BUBBLING)
- (SCREAMING)
(LAUGHING)
- Oh, boy!
- Oh, Mae, well done.
- This guy's got some size to him.
- I did it!
He's going to cook up nicely!
Yes, he would, if I weren't
throwing him back.
Wh-what?!
- Set him free.
- Is this because of what I said earlier?
He can't breathe.
I was gonna make you
my famous Bass Benedict
for breakfast tomorrow.
Well, I want pancakes.
Okay, give him a kiss
before he goes back.
- No, thanks. You can kiss him for me.
- (CHUCKLING)
All right. Well, this little guy's
going to have a hell of a story to tell.
(GROANS)
All right. Well, I guess we're not
going to be fishing buddies, huh?
Well, that's not really the kind of
buddy I was looking for anyway...
- Oh, no. What kind of buddy were you looking for?
- No.
(KISSING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
- Is everything okay?
- Yeah, I...
Let me guess. You need to take it?
Lady gets a prize...
(CHUCKLING) I'll just meet
you up at the house.
Hey, did you find Vasili? You all right?
- Yeah.
- Where are you?
- I can't tell you that.
- Why?
Vasili is not in a very, uh...
trusting mood just yet.
- Well, I'll come personally.
- No, that includes you.
Why doesn't Vasili trust me?
I guess he figures the mole
could be just about anyone.
And he's feeling very paranoid.
And he is alive, and I think
he'd like to stay that way.
Doesn't he know who the mole is?
Isn't that what started all this?
He was bluffing. He said he
knew that there was a mole...
- Just not who it is.
- How?
His, uh... his friend told him.
Arkady Volk.
My father was a plumber.
He said you could trace a leak...
by adding different colors to the
water that flows through the pipes.
Then you go to where the leak
is and see what color comes out.
(COUGHING)
Watch out for the bones.
I knew one of us was helping the enemy
and I remembered my father's words.
We gave different code names
for my CIA undercover officer...
to each of our people...
... to find out which of them
kept meeting Robin Larkin.
Are you okay?
- You got Canary.
- She's can't breathe.
Yes, that's the intention.
(GLASS SHATTERING)
This is the antidote. Admit
what you did, and you get it.
- Give it to her.
- Are you a traitor?
She admits it.
- Exactly, and this is her punishment.
- Give her the antidote.
Which antidote?
Breathe!
(SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
No, no, no, no, no. (SPEAKS RUSSIAN)
(PANTING)
She was working for the CIA.
Why did you make me
watch, you sick bastard?
- Sorry, I need to get this.
- (PHONE RINGING)
- (RINGING CONTINUES)
- (DOOR SLIDES OPEN)
- You motherfucker, it was you.
- What was me?
You told Sirin about me.
Turner is with Sirin, we just spoke.
- Where are they now?
- I don't know.
And I don't care, because
Sirin doesn't know my name.
What?
You don't even remember
what you told him, do you?
You must have been shit-faced.
You told Sirin you had an
asset operating inside the CIA
but you never told him my name.
- Sirin's been bluffing.
- I should have told you.
You should have kept
your fucking mouth shut!
But, you know what, I don't care.
I'm out. I'm done. I'm retired.
Won't that look suspicious?
My best friend just got arrested
for being a double agent.
No-one's going to question the timing.
- We should talk about it.
- No, no, no.
I'm done talking. You
just about got me burned.
If that got back to Moscow,
that wouldn't look too good for you.
Have a nice life.
(BEEPING)
- (HONKING)
- (BIRDS CHIRPING)
What have you got for me?
It's about Thrush's
investigation into you.
The investigation was culminated
without any substantive findings.
Well, I guess it's been reopened.
- Hmm.
- It will cost you ten.
Pigeons are synanthropes,
like squirrels, raccoons, rats.
They thrive in environments
made by humans.
Generally considered to be pests.
Synanthropes are tolerated, but unloved.
You really hurt my feelings.
(SIREN BLARING)
- Five.
- Eight.
Seven.
Senator Thrush is pursuing
an obstruction of justice
charge against you.
- How?
- Someone gave a sealed deposition.
Her name is Mae Barber. That
name mean anything to you?
I'll send the money around.
Do it soon. It'll be
harder to do from prison.
- Sorry, mom, this is for work.
- (PHONE RINGING)
I'll be right back.
- Hello.
- We're going to war. Get ready.
- With a 17-year-old boy?
- And the mother.
_
I know people. I know people
in counter intelligence.
I know people in the
deputy director's office.
These people can actually protect you.
All those resources are inside the CIA.
As long as the mole is out there...
It's better if I just disappear.
Hey, I thought you planned
to pay for your passage.
Not with my life.
But you're willing to watch
people pay with theirs?
Not to mention all the people who
are still suffering on your behalf.
History has known
less fair arrangements.
I'm sorry I lied, but I've been
helping the CIA for years.
You don't think I was
expendable in their eyes?
When I told them my life was
in danger, they sent you...
and the passport of a man
who doesn't even look like me.
I risked my life for your country.
Fuck it, then.
- We need to get to Volk. It's the only way.
- It's not possible.
He's the only one who knows
the identity of the mole.
You won't get near him.
Maybe, but I think I
know someone who can.
Leave her out of this.
She's done enough. She's
been pushed past her limit.
Yeah, well, it's only
when we're at the limit
that we discover what
we're truly capable of.
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- (SOBBING)
(WATER RUNNING)
(CUP CLATTERS ON TABLE)
(MUSIC CONTINUES)
(SIGHS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(DOOR OPENS)
The overwatch team's in place, ma'am.
It was said that King
Solomon was especially fond
of a loyal servant by the name of Ahiah.
One day King Solomon entertained
the angel of death in his court.
And he noticed a strange
look on Death's face,
when he saw Ahiah pouring wine.
Later, when they were alone,
Solomon asked him about it
and Death admitted that he
had been surprised to see Ahiah
for he was on Death's
list for the very next day.
Later that night,
when Death left the court,
Solomon sent his servant away,
insisting that he ride
all the way to Arabia
to flee his date with Death.
That was the last time
Solomon saw Ahiah.
But the next time Solomon
saw the Angel of Death
Death told him a funny story.
I am drunk.
(CHUCKLING)
I thought you said you
were never drinking again.
I lied.
He said he was surprised to see
Ahiah that day in Solomon's court
because he hadn't been expecting
to find the servant in Jerusalem.
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
- Thank you.
- That's great.
- Wow.
- Thank you.
I see you have no problem eating fish,
when someone else catches it.
You've exposed my hypocrisy.
It must have been fun to
catch this big motherfucker.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
I think this is the biggest
fish I have ever seen.
It's gigantic.
The Angel of Death was surprised
to find Ahiah in Jerusalem...
because he had been planning to
meet him the next day in Arabia.
Mmm.
It's delicious. Are you going
to take a bite of that salmon?
Yeah, yeah.
So, the wise king in trying to
help Ahiah escape his destiny
sends his favorite
servant to the very place,
where Death was waiting for him.
I wonder what he did to
the servants he didn't like, hmm?
So, what does this story mean? Yeah?
It means...
(INDISTINCT WHISPERING)
Thank you.
- Sam Barber?
- Yeah?
You're under arrest.
Stand up for me, spin around and
put your hands behind your back.
Stay there, right there.
Spread and hold still for me.
(HANDCUFFS CLICKING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(CAR PASSING BY)
(BRAKES SQUEALING)
Ekaterina.
I think we have a friend in common.
I need your help.