Previously on "Condor"...
- He changed his mind, wants to help.
- Help how?
He's going over the files.
He thinks Gordon's been set up.
I have an asset inside the SVR.
A week ago he passed me a file
indicating that Gordon Piper was
working with the Russians.
I can't do this anymore.
I feel like they know.
When you contact the CIA,
you must not say that I helped you.
I need to ask you for one last favor.
I'm suggesting that the mole's
treachery is getting people killed...
... and causing other damage in
ways we cannot begin to know.
So as much as we may dislike
each other personally...
I don't have a personal
opinion about you.
So as much as I dislike you personally,
I showed you my report
in the spirit of openness.
This is the same photo
from Bob's office.
And you can plant fake files,
but how do you make an
innocent man take a payoff?
Gordon took money from a
Russian intelligent agent.
- No more waiting.
- I agree. Just...
Can you do me a favor?
The pizza's here.
I asked them to let me be
the one to come and get you.
Tracy, I don't know what
the fuck you're talking about.
Lior Lishkott. You took money from him.
The Americans will be looking for you.
You are going to have
to go away for a while.
How long do I have to go away for?
- The ambulance.
- What ambulance?
How'd they get it?
- Where'd you get the ambulance?
- Rented it.
Your friend...
the one who's alive. Is he
going to tell anyone my name?
He doesn't know your name.
- Synced and corrected by Firefly -
- www.addic7ed.com -
Yeah.
Hi.
There's been a development I
thought you'd want to know about.
- Gordon's been picked up.
- Okay.
- I'll come meet you.
- I'm out front.
I feel terrible for
what I've done to him.
You didn't do anything
to him. You defended him.
That's what I keep telling myself.
This is on Gordon.
You're not responsible.
I keep telling myself that, too.
And it was his decisions
that led him here.
But, I didn't try and help him.
I saw him getting worse.
The drinking and the money problems
and the fights with Eva...
He was hurting. I didn't reach out.
I did the opposite.
You should have seen the way
Eva looked at me when I
walked him out of the house.
Like she wanted to kill me. His kids...
If Gordon is innocent, we
will have a chance to prove it.
- Has he said anything?
- Mm. Completely isolated.
Robin's gonna let him sit overnight...
and question him in the morning.
I still believe that Gordon was set up.
I don't know what I believe any more.
Anything on the ambulance?
They were still setting up
a spreadsheet when I left.
All right. Well...
'Til the morning.
I've missed you, my friend.
I wish the circumstances were better.
No. At least it looks as though
your people have taken the bait.
They're not my people.
There may still be a problem.
- Who?
- Joe Turner.
He recognized the photo from the file
I planted in Partidge's office.
- He is smart.
- I'll handle it.
No, if anything happened to Turner,
it'll only bring more heat.
I'm keeping him close. He trusts me.
If it needs to be done, I'll do it.
There's another loose end to tie.
The guy we used for
the Sirin job, Dan Letts...
I don't think he could ID me, but...
Why take the chance?
Any word from Moscow on
how Sirin found out about me?
We're investigating.
You're going to have to stay here.
You've earned your retirement:
nice apartment in Moscow...
dacha in the country,
money, whatever you want.
The timing's not good. I've met someone.
- I'm thinking about getting out.
- Getting out?
- You could be seen as a liability.
- Is that a threat?
Not by me.
- You think I'm gonna become a triple agent?
- The risk...
I don't have any reason
to say anything to anybody...
... and every reason not to.
When we first met, you were
a man with thwarted ambitions...
... and a burning desire
to do something great.
That never goes away,
even if it goes dormant for a while.
I'm not that man anymore.
I want a simple life now.
Moscow may not allow it.
Why does Moscow care where I retire?
If you were in Moscow,
you could let the world know...
... the extent of our
penetration into the CIA.
That in itself is a
public relations coup.
This isn't about Moscow.
This is about you,
and you want the credit.
I want us to get the credit.
All that work... all those years...
What were they for?
_
Is he okay?
- Does he look okay?
- Shit, man.
What the fuck happened?
_
Where the fuck are you, dude?
If I call and I call, call me back!
I'm really fucking scared.
I think... someone's watching me.
Damn...
Would you like some dessert?
If you have any heart medication,
now would be the time to take it.
Do you have to get that?
Well, it's just my assistant.
She's, uh... checking up on me.
I'll call her in the morning.
So would you like to
see the rest of the house?
I don't believe you've
been upstairs yet.
I'd like that very much.
- Does that feel good?
- Oh, yeah...
- Are you expecting someone?
- No.
- Hi, Carla.
- Sorry to show up unannounced.
- I tried calling a few times.
- What's wrong?
I got a call from a
contact over at the FBI.
Their embed at the CIMC has taken
one of our people into custody.
Who?
Gordon Piper.
Oh, fucking hilarious!
You think this is funny?
This shit could kill me!
Fucking assholes!
Come in.
Watching anything good?
- Good morning.
- I thought you'd be happier to see me.
You've just taken one of
my people into custody.
A mole operating right
under my nose for years.
What good is winning
if you don't get to gloat?
Don't hurt me, I come in peace.
I'm taking Jude to school.
Do you need a lift?
- No, I'll ride my bike.
- Okay.
Why are you all dressed up?
- I have an important meeting today.
- With who?
I'm going to talk to someone
about Reuel Abbott.
I've been thinking
about what you said...
... and if there's a way
to hold him accountable...
... for what he's done to this family...
... I'm gonna see that it gets done.
Good.
I want you to promise me that
you're going to stay away from him.
He's an evil old prick and I don't
know what he's capable of.
- Say it.
- I promise.
Okay.
Oh. I'll get my camera.
You look nice when you want to.
I'm having lunch with a friend.
Hmm.
- I'm gonna go get ready for school.
- See you.
Okay.
Thought maybe you stayed
over at your lady friend's again.
Oh, no, it was more
of a one-night thing.
Well, you have a way of making
temporary things permanent.
Yeah.
- I'll see you later.
- See you.
I'm waiting to hear back from them.
We'll see you at the club.
I'm on my way.
It's all about who you know...
You sprung for the premium package, huh?
This isn't like Tinder.
You need references from two members
and then there's this
whole approval process.
- Jesus!
- Yeah, Jesus couldn't even get on this dating app, bro.
Good morning.
- Oh. Hey, man.
- Hey.
This is an FBI matter now.
We're shutting down the site.
Yeah, I know. I'm just wondering
how you got on with that ambulance.
Ambulance?
Yeah, we put together a
database of rental companies...
- ... but that's about it.
- Can I get a copy?
Well, the hard drives are packed away.
You know we already got the guy, right?
I know. But it's important.
- Yeah. I can find it for you.
- All right.
- Good morning.
- Hey.
- Measuring your mark?
- I've got this one all sized up.
He's not much different
than anyone else with a penis.
Just a bit more extreme.
Really?
Deep down every man believes
in his own unique specialness.
- I think it's a flaw in your gender.
- Thinking we're special?
Thinking that your specialness
has gone unrecognized by everyone else.
That's why someone turns traitor.
To win back that specialness.
If a spy is someone who keeps secrets...
... a mole is someone who
keeps secrets from other spies.
What could be more special that that?
I'm going to break him.
I'm going to give him no choice...
... but to defend himself with a
declaration of his own importance.
He already looks pretty broken.
What are you waiting for?
Reuel Abbott's in the building.
He had to step away for a few minutes.
- I guess nothing stays a secret for long.
- Well, it's okay.
That way we get to kill
two birds with one stone.
- The other bird being?
- Him learning to fear me.
- How are you doing?
- I feel a crippling guilt.
But other than that, great.
This isn't anybody's fault but Gordon's.
I know.
Thank you very much.
Anyone good in this movie of yours?
You know my nephew Sammy?
Ah. So, it's a student film?
That kid is amazing. He edits
all the effects on his laptop.
- Kids these days...
- Right.
I just saw in the newspaper
that a 12-year-old girl just got
into Harvard Medical School.
Huh.
- There she is.
- _
- No, no, this is not what I'm looking for.
- It's an ambulance.
Yeah. No, the kid's got
a real specific vision.
All right then.
I myself am in between cars.
I don't suppose you've got
something I could rent, do you?
Sure, we can scrounge you up a car.
Cool.
Sorry for the hold up.
Did I miss anything good?
No, she's waited for you.
You know, she wants to give me
a taste of my own fate, huh?
Well, that's... that's at the
heart of any good drama,
don't you think?
Getting to imagine yourself
standing in somebody else's shoes...
It's... I look forward to it, really.
You have a lighter attitude
about this than I expected.
I do, don't I? I feel lighter.
Robin?
This has all been a giant...
giant misunderstanding.
Lior Lishkott and I are
going into business together.
It's all above board.
I just couldn't report it up the
ladder until I was sure it was real.
You understand that?
The money was just an
advance against my salary.
We were... going to lose the house.
Are you going to... pull this
intimidation bullshit with me?
The least you can do is,
show me a little dignity.
How dignified is it to
take money from a man
with direct ties to Russian
intelligence, Gordon?
Bullshit.
It's all in there. Lior's business
is financed by the Kremlin.
He's an SVR asset.
I... I didn't know.
Right. You're just a spy.
It's not like it's your business
to know such things.
How many blown ops have
you been a part of recently?
Belgrade, Dubrovnik...
- the Ukrainian op last week.
- What?
I mean, how much loss
of life and spilled blood
- are we talking about here?
- Robin...
You know me.
I think we are well beyond
that assumption, Gordo.
Look, I know how bad it looks, but
what's the logical explanation?
That I suddenly turned
against my country
after more than a
decade of loyal service...
... or that I did
something fucking stupid?
Those aren't mutually
exclusive possibilities.
And if I was to believe that
you were just stupid...
... you'd have to be
pretty fucking stupid!
I swear. I am loyal.
- More than a decade, huh?
- Yes.
What year did you join the Agency?
Come on, you know the answer to that.
You don't like my answers, so why
don't we start hearing yours?
2005.
- Why did you join?
- Robin...
I'm trying to figure out where it
all went wrong for you, Gordon.
Why did you join the CIA?
Go back to being a kid, who
didn't know what their future was...
... and who never could have imagined
where life was going to take him.
- Jay Atwood?
- Are you the new waiter?
- No, I...
- Okay, I was kidding.
I can tell you're not the new waiter.
You're clearly American.
Who are you? Why do I care?
Your secretary said you'd be down here.
Said you don't spend
much time in the office.
This is my office and I've got a
twelve o'clock meeting, so...
I'm your twelve o'clock.
Your office... your other office
said you'd be expecting me.
Tracy Crane...
You're Tracy Crane. Ah, shit!
You were expecting a woman?
Yeah... yeah, I was expecting a...
Got dressed up, showered and everything.
Welcome to Athens. Jay Attwood.
You hungry? You want some lunch?
- Yeah, sure.
- Bring him the special...
Sit down.
The food here is excellent,
but Athens station is
pure loukaniko party.
- You know what a loukaniko is?
- No.
Loukaniko is sausage.
What I'm saying is that
Athens is a sausage party.
I thought we were
getting some new talent.
Sorry to disappoint.
- So, is this your first posting?
- Yeah.
Well, Athens is a good place
to pop your cherry.
Maybe you'd rather pop her cherry? Huh?
I'm married. We have a three year old.
And the guy's got an
answer for everything...
So? Why'd you join the you know what?
I'm talking about the CIA.
To serve my country. Something
that's intellectually stimu...
No, no, no. No, stop. Come on.
Don't give me the bullshit answer.
- You already got the job.
- I was... I'm not...
Come on. When you were six
years old, what did you want to be?
- Fireman?
- Astronaut.
Yeah? So what are you still
doing down here on earth?
I think I internalized at a
young age that I was special.
That I had the potential to do
something important in the world.
And I've never really
let go of that idea.
One too many attaboys, huh?
All right. All right. Now,
we're getting someplace.
Thank you for seeing me, Senator Thrush.
Reuel Abbott is a very powerful man.
I understand your concern.
I don't imagine there are many
people who have seen his dark side...
... and are willing to talk about it.
Reuel has been operating
out of bounds for far too long.
The American people deserve
to know the truth about anyone
we entrust with such awesome power.
I want to show you that I will
do everything within my power...
to protect you from the
possibility of retribution.
But if it's too much for you,
if you need more time,
you're having doubts...
I don't want to pressure
you into saying something,
you're not ready to say.
No... I'm ready.
Well?
You know, I have been to every lot
between here and Baltimore...
looking for this exact ambulance.
It was just used in a bank heist movie.
- Oh yeah? What was the name of the film?
- I don't remember.
You don't remember the name
of the guy who rented it from you?
I maintain strict confidentiality
with all my customers.
So, what's your film all about?
Oh, I'm not making a movie.
Neither was the guy
that rented this from you.
Movies use blanks. This
was used for something else.
If you give me the renter's information,
your part in this ends here.
I didn't question Sam's
death until Iris came along.
Iris Loramer?
She told me that Sam was involved
in the death of her husband
and she had proof.
She'd filmed them together.
I saw it.
My husband who I thought I knew
ordering the death
of one of our friends.
I know that you've seen it.
Now I'd like you to unsee it.
Go get it for me. Put it in my hand.
Once you accused me
of threatening your family.
At that time it was the
furthest thing from my mind.
- So you gave it to him... the media card?
- What else could I do?
They can kill you and
make it look like an accident.
I know that I shouldn't
have given it to him.
I was just so scared.
You did the right thing at the time...
and you're doing the right thing now.
It's Tracy. Leave a message.
It's me. I've found the ambulance.
I've got the guy's address
and I'm on my way there.
Call me back.
How long have you been married?
Oh, I love it here!
I found this cute little bazaar,
and then Anders...
What are you doing?
I just realized... that
Anders is asleep.
So, what? You don't want
to hear about my day?
Oh, no, no, no. I'm very
good at multi-tasking.
Tell me... about that bazaar.
Sorry.
Have you ever noticed that all NFL
quarterbacks could be models?
No, but I'm guessing that you've
got a theory on the subject.
Great leaders are not born.
They're made.
Okay. They are bred with
years of confidence-building,
starting all the way
back at the playground.
How many times have you
heard the sentence growing up...
"You're going to be a
heart-breaker, Tracy". Right?
That sense of specialness... that
you internalized in your youth.
That's a self-fulfilling prophecy.
It's the same shit that
they said to Tom Brady.
An interesting theory.
Okay, I got to take a piss.
Baby, come here.
Where we going?
- I'm leaving Athens.
- Wh-Why?
Because you're a fucking shit!
That came in the mail today.
- Baby...
- Fucking asshole.
- I thought you were married.
- Huh?
They sent us a copy.
They send one to your wife?
Fucking Russians, man. I am sorry.
- Russians?
- She was a honey pot.
I thought you were slick.
I thought you were Tom Brady.
Did she leave you?
Went back to Virginia.
Well, you won't be too far behind her,
so maybe you'll want her back.
What?
Your flight leaves at 8 AM tomorrow.
Pack what you need. I'll have
the rest shipped over to you.
- No. I don't understand.
- C'mon man.
You're a smart guy. We're
taking you off the field.
You've had a pretty mediocre career.
Things didn't go exactly as planned,
but that doesn't make me traitor.
But taking money from
a Russian asset does.
Lior played me.
No, I bet my career that you're dirty.
I thought he was just ex-Mossad,
I didn't know shit
about Russia. He said...
He said I was the business
partner he was looking for. He...
He stroked my ego. I fell for it. I...
- I needed the money.
- We all need the money.
- You have to believe me.
- No.
You have to convince me. And
you are not very convincing.
Frankly, the only part I'm
having a hard time believing
is how anybody can be such a loser.
Fuck you, Robin.
- You okay?
- Sorry, Gordon is a friend.
No apology necessary. It's...
Never easy to learn that a friend
isn't who you thought they were.
_
Matty? Open up.
Matty?
Fuck!
You were there that day.
You were in the car with him.
I can explain.
- The fuck you do?
- I can explain!
Why'd you kill Matty?
Because of the Russians?
Because you guys
were working together...
He's dead!
- What?
- We didn't kill him.
- We were gonna make a hand-off.
- Wait, wait, wait, What?
You didn't... He's alive?!
- We was gonna hand him over, man!
- To who? The Russians?
The Russians? We
were working for the CIA.
Who at the CIA?
- You fucking with my head, man!
- I'm on your side.
I'm on your side.
And that's not such a good place
to be, 'cause everyone's dead!
Hey. Calm down. You
need to hear me. Okay?
I'm unarmed.
Do you have any idea how
many unarmed men I've killed?
One or two...
Don't fucking move! Stay
on the fucking ground!
I'm a federal agent.
My name is Joe Turner.
Joe Turner?
You were in the car with Sirin,
when that whole deal went down.
Dale Fridrych, FBI.
I got a lead on Letts here.
An informant who said...
him and his crew were
contracted to kill Sirin.
What? No, not kill, kidnap.
And he got away.
- So, Sirin's alive?
- I-I think so.
- Any idea where he is?
- No.
You're bleeding.
I got a first aid kit in my
truck. Hang here a minute.
What the fuck is going on?
It's Tracy. Leave a message.
I am impressed. Your little speech
brought Mr. Crane to tears.
Tracy's too close to the case.
He tried to persuade me
Gordon was being set up
by the Russians to
protect the real infiltrator.
Tracy is a good man, and good
men like to think the best of others.
Not like us.
_
Leave a message.
Two dead guys. Our guy's
skull is cracked open.
Probably a drug deal gone wrong.
But, he's going on about
how we can't arrest him,
because he works for the government.
- Excuse me?
- Yes.
I'm here for Joseph Turner.
- You're his lawyer?
- No, I'm the deputy director of the CIA.
I checked. There is no Dale
Fridrych working for the CIMC.
The Russians are cleaning
up after themselves.
What... cleaning up on?
They set up Gordon to
protect their actual inside man.
This whole fucking thing has
been one big active measure.
If this is a disinformation campaign,
you and Mrs. Larkin really
stepped into it, didn't you?
No? What are you going to do now?
Hmm?
Oh, if Sirin's alive
and you can find him,
maybe he can tell you who the mole is.
Too bad you didn't pick a
place to meet in the event,
things didn't go as planned.
Tradecraft?
101.
I'm not the only one who
made an obvious mistake.
Am I? You were in Bob's office,
the night that he died.
Why didn't you go through his files?
Maybe I was overcome by grief.
Yeah, or maybe you have a reason
to hang Gordon Piper out to dry.
Good night.
- What can I get you?
- Bourbon. Neat.
It makes sense that a man who
was once burned would fear fire.
- Do we know each other?
- Of course I know you, Tracy.
Sorry, I don't remember you.
That's because we've never met.
But I've been looking for someone
like you for a very long time.
I think you mistake me for someone else.
No, I don't think so.
There you go.
_
I need to see you.
Food time!
- Where's Dad?
- He's still at work. C'mon, let's eat.
You've been crying, huh?
Yeah, I've had a hell of a day, too.
Thank you for coming.
You and I should go away together.
- When?
- Right now.
- It's crazy... I can't.
- It makes perfect sense to me.
We'll leave as soon as you're packed.
I have children. Someone
has to drive them and feed them...
... and stand over them
when they do their homework.
Ask your mom to look after them.
- I've a shift tomorrow.
- Get another doctor to cover it.
You just have an answer
for everything, huh?
No, just us two things.
If we leave right now, we
can be there before midnight.
- Where?
- It's a surprise.
Well then how would I know what to pack?
Just bring one of everything.
Attention.
This is the boarding call for train...
Joe? My name is Ekaterina.
My American friends call me Kat.
We have a friend in common.
Where is Vasili?
He sent me.
Let's get moving, so we don't
draw attention to ourselves.